<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sinne.link/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://sinne.link/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-10-29T18:13:59+00:00</updated><id>https://sinne.link/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Under Sinnelleos’ Deadlight</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">The Catcher in the Rye, my thoughts</title><link href="https://sinne.link/blog/2025/catcher-in-the-rye-thoughts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Catcher in the Rye, my thoughts"/><published>2025-10-29T17:37:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-29T17:37:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sinne.link/blog/2025/catcher-in-the-rye-thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sinne.link/blog/2025/catcher-in-the-rye-thoughts/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://sinne.link/books/catcher-in-the-rye">Book in question</a>.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/5add7591561375.5e34b20cf1e57-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/5add7591561375.5e34b20cf1e57-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/5add7591561375.5e34b20cf1e57-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/5add7591561375.5e34b20cf1e57.gif" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Still from <a href="https://www.behance.net/tsaeyungwu">Kelly Wu</a>'s animation in <a href="https://www.behance.net/gallery/91561375/Catcher-in-the-Rye-short-film">Behance</a> </div> <p>Oh Holden. How would I have loved to meet you sooner. I’m glad I finally got around to reading <em>The Catcher in the Rye</em>. Being the weeb I am, the first time I saw it referenced was in the slogan of the Laughing Man in <em>Ghost in the Shell: Stand Alone Complex</em>.</p> <blockquote> <p>I thought what I’d do was, I’d pretend I was one of those deaf-mutes.</p> </blockquote> <p>It’s also mentioned in one of my guilty pleasure movies, <em>The Perks of Being a Wallflower</em>. And my starter ship in <em>Azur Lane</em>, Z23, has a skin called <em>The Eyecatch in the Rye?</em> So I really didn’t need any more reasons to read it. Also, if you’ve ever heard of a guy called John Lennon, apparently this book was his killer’s favorite. How crazily interconnected this world is.</p> <p>The main question I had going into <em>The Catcher in the Rye</em> was how the hell a coming-of-age novel became such a huge classic. Sooner rather than later, the answer became obvious. <em>The Catcher in the Rye</em> is not just <em>a</em> coming-of-age novel. It might as well be <em>the</em> coming-of-age novel. Most literature of this genre is corny, and if you are outside its main target audience, they really aren’t that enjoyable to read.</p> <p>But Holden is not corny, he’s <strong>sincere</strong>. The book is not dark, it’s <strong>raw</strong>. And when one writes as close to the human heart as Salinger did, I think it’s impossible for anyone to read it and not feel appalled when presented with Holden’s struggles. The alienation from his peers. Everything being <em>lousy</em> and everyone being a <em>phony</em>. Even if it’s been a few years since I was in Holden’s shoes, I can very well sympathize with the pessimism he faces the world with. While reading it, I couldn’t help but think that he and I could be good friends. We are similar in a lot of ways. Except Holden is awfully sociable for a guy who despises everyone so much. And then there’s the fact that Holden is <em>bitter</em>. You need to have a special kind of resentment to remember everyone just by the things about them that bother you, <em>for Chrissake</em>.</p> <p>Despite it all, Holden doesn’t wall off his heart. He still has his sense of justice. He takes note of all the things that depress him. He doesn’t go out of his way to mess with people. On the contrary, he’s kind enough to reward those that don’t piss him off <em>that much</em>. He grew on me, he really did, that <em>sonuvabitch</em>.</p> <p><em>The Catcher in the Rye</em> is a wonderful story about a young man that is coming to terms with how the innocence, sincerity, and curiosity of children slowly drifts away as they grow older. Not only in his peers but also himself. A book that carefully and skillfully shows how family, school, mentors, friends, lovers, and topics such as pride, mental health, sex, and mortality influence the heart of a young man.</p> <p>I’ll leave you with another classic quote from the book:</p> <blockquote> <p>The mark of the immature man is that he wants to die nobly for a cause, while the mark of the mature man is that he wants to live humbly for one.</p> </blockquote>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="book reviews"/><category term="classics"/><category term="fiction"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My impressions after reading "The Catcher in the Rye" by J.D. Salinger.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exploración de la Patagonia sur I, my thoughts</title><link href="https://sinne.link/blog/2025/exploracion-patagonia-1-thoughts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploración de la Patagonia sur I, my thoughts"/><published>2025-10-29T12:32:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-29T12:32:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sinne.link/blog/2025/exploracion-patagonia-1-thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sinne.link/blog/2025/exploracion-patagonia-1-thoughts/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://sinne.link/books/exploracion-patagonia-1">Book in question</a>.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/clouds-5367864_1920-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/clouds-5367864_1920-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/clouds-5367864_1920-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/clouds-5367864_1920.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Picture from <a href="https://pixabay.com/es/users/sandrocisternas-5020022/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=5367864">Sandro</a> in <a href="https://pixabay.com/es//?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=5367864">Pixabay</a> </div> <p>This book was a gift from a coworker who was getting rid of stuff after spring cleaning. I was hoping for a bit more sea navigation stories, but there were enough mentions of Piedrabuena with his <em>Santa Cruz</em>, and FitzRoy with his <em>Beagle</em> to make me happy.</p> <p>Nevertheless, I have no idea how high school kids (in Argentina, of course) aren’t reading a book like this. It combines history, geography, and natural science in equal parts. Not ashamed to say that I got a better understanding of my esteemed Patagonia’s topography from this book than I did from my geography classes. And I don’t know about you, but I think the contact between indigenous peoples and the white man is one of the most interesting interactions to read about (when they are not heavily editorialized, at least).</p> <p>I’ve traveled a lot along the eastern shore of Patagonia, and I believe anyone who has done so will laugh, marvel, and find comfort in the words of Moreno. It’s such an underrated landscape. I don’t blame anyone who prefers the mountains and trees of Bariloche, Esquel, or the views you get around Lago Fagnano. But beauty truly is in the eye of the beholder. And when you stop in the goddamn middle of nothing, look around, and are able to appreciate an ecosystem that maybe not thrives, but survives, despite what little nature has given, <strong>I think that’s beauty.</strong></p> <p>There’s a second part of this book, originally called <em>Viaje a la Patagonia Austral</em> (Journey to Southern Patagonia), which supposedly expands on Moreno’s takes about the republic’s interests in what at the time were distant lands. I’m sure I’ll get to it eventually. Although it does feel odd dropping into the calm right before the storm, with the Conquest of the Desert taking place only a year after Moreno’s expedition. I’d be more interested in reading the buildup to the tension that Moreno had to navigate before diving into Roca’s infamous campaign.</p> <p>What an interesting man, Moreno. It’s nothing but awe-inspiring to read about a 24-year-old with such passion for the pursuit of knowledge as to leave aside the comfort the elite class enjoyed in Buenos Aires to come to Patagonia, eat small game, sleep among <em>matorrales</em> under the rain, and hope not to get killed by a puma or a drunk <em>indio</em>. Truly a national hero.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="book reviews"/><category term="Argentina"/><category term="Patagonia"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My impressions after reading "Exploración de la Patagonia sur I" by Francisco P. Moreno.]]></summary></entry></feed>