<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://sinne.link/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://sinne.link/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-10-29T13:27:09+00:00</updated><id>https://sinne.link/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Under Sinnelleos’ Deadlight</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Exploración de la Patagonia sur I, my thoughts</title><link href="https://sinne.link/blog/2025/exploracion-de-la-patagonia-sur-1-thoughts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploración de la Patagonia sur I, my thoughts"/><published>2025-10-29T12:32:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-29T12:32:00+00:00</updated><id>https://sinne.link/blog/2025/exploracion-de-la-patagonia-sur-1-thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://sinne.link/blog/2025/exploracion-de-la-patagonia-sur-1-thoughts/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://sinne.link/books/exploracion_patagonia_1">Book in question.</a></p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/clouds-5367864_1920-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/clouds-5367864_1920-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/clouds-5367864_1920-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/clouds-5367864_1920.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Picture from <a href="https://pixabay.com/es/users/sandrocisternas-5020022/?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=5367864">Sandro Cisternas</a> in <a href="https://pixabay.com/es//?utm_source=link-attribution&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=image&amp;utm_content=5367864">Pixabay</a> </div> <p>This book was a gift from a coworker who was getting rid of stuff after spring cleaning. I was hoping for a bit more sea navigation stories, but there were enough mentions of Piedrabuena with his <em>Santa Cruz</em>, and FitzRoy with his <em>Beagle</em> to make me happy.</p> <p>Nevertheless, I have no idea how high school kids (in Argentina, of course) aren’t reading a book like this. It combines history, geography, and natural science in equal parts. Not ashamed to say that I got a better overview of my esteemed Patagonia’s topography from this book than I did from my geography classes. And I don’t know about you, but I think the contact between indigenous people and the white man is one of the most interesting interactions to read about (when they are not heavily editorialized, at least).</p> <p>I’ve traveled a lot along the eastern shore of Patagonia, and I believe anyone who has done so will laugh, marvel, and find comfort in the words of Moreno. It’s such an underrated landscape. I don’t blame anyone who prefers the mountains and trees of Bariloche, Esquel, or the views you get around Lago Fagnano. But beauty truly is in the eye of the beholder. And when you stop in the goddamn middle of nothing, look around, and are able to appreciate an ecosystem that maybe not thrives, but survives, despite what little nature has given, I think that’s beauty.</p> <p>There’s a second part of this book, originally called <em>Viaje a la Patagonia Austral</em> (Journey to Southern Patagonia), which supposedly expands on Moreno’s takes about the republic’s interests in what at the time were distant lands. I’m sure I’ll get to it eventually. Although it does feel odd dropping into the calm right before the storm, with the Conquest of the Desert taking place only a year after Moreno’s expedition. I’d be more interested in reading the buildup to the tension that Moreno had to navigate before diving into Roca’s infamous campaign.</p> <p>What an interesting man, Moreno. It’s nothing but awe-inspiring to read about a 24-year-old with such passion for the pursuit of knowledge as to leave aside the comfort the elite class enjoyed in Buenos Aires to come to Patagonia, eat small game, sleep among the <em>matorrales</em> under the rain, and hope not to get killed by a puma or a drunk <em>indio</em>. Truly a national hero.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="book reviews"/><category term="Argentina"/><category term="Patagonia"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My impressions after reading "Exploración de la Patagonia sur I" by Francisco P. Moreno.]]></summary></entry></feed>